# **Mohamed Hamed Ahmed**

Data Analyst Location: Dubai

### **Contact Information**

Email: mokaml98210@gmail.com - Phone: +971 503325126

LinkedIn: Mohamed Hamed - GitHub: mokaml9821

# **Summary**

I'm a friendly person with strong communication skills, able to work well within a team and lead them to great process, communicate well and professionally with the different cultures because of my work as a CSR for more than 5 years. Also, I'm a Data Analyst with a strong background in data preparation, visualization, and reporting using Python, SQL, Excel, and Power BI. Proven ability to uncover insights and drive business decisions with clean and reliable data processing

### **Soft Skills**

- Strong communication and problem-solving skills.
- Eager to continuously learn and improve.
- Goal-oriented and multi-tasker person
- Statistical analysis skills.

#### **Job Skills**

- Proficient in Python (Pandas, NumPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly), SQL, Power BI, and Excel (Pivot Tables, Power Query, DAX).
- Data Analysis: Data preparation, cleaning, and analysis using Python and Power Query.
- Database Management: MySQL.
- Data Visualization: Creating dashboards using Excel and Power BI.

## **Experience**

# **Data Analyst** – Freelance Projects

- Analyzed datasets to uncover insights, improving decision-making. Developed interactive dashboards using Power BI.
- Built SQL queries to extract data from relational databases.
- Cleaned and transformed raw data by Python and Power Query, ensuring accuracy and reliability for key reports., improving reporting accuracy (ETL processes).
- Designed and presented visual reports using Power BI and Excel.
- Delivered insights that increased sales conversion.

# **Customer Happiness Executive** – Dubai Electricity and Water Authority (DEWA) **Jan 2022 till now**

### **Used Tools: (SAP, Teams, Avaya and MS Outlook)**

- Helping all types of customers (consumers-contractors-suppliers) to solve their problems with the services that company providing it after checked their documents in accordance with the Authority's rules and policies.
- Handling customers complaints, providing timely solutions and alternatives to reaching a compromise between customer needs and the Authority's policies.

# Customer Service Representative – Talabat

Jan 2019 - Oct 2021

# Used Tools: (Salesforce, BackOffice application, Zoiper, MS Outlook and Zoom)

- Helping Talabat customers (at different seven Arab countries) to solve their problems with restaurants in such cases (delayed orders, missing items, bad food quality, etc...).
- Promptly addressing concerns between customers and Talabat drivers.
- Promoted within 18 months from CSR agent to team leader due to my strong performance and organizational impact.
- Trained, mentored all new staff and documented their performance.
- Contact and handle the angry customers who asked to escalate their problems or request callback from responsible manager because of a major problem.

### Certifications

- Data Analytics Certificate Keymaster British Institute.
- Python & SQL diploma for Data Analysis Agartha Academy Certificate.
- Data Analysis Diploma in Excel and Power BI Institute of Management Professional.
- Advanced Excel Certificate Mr. Excel Online Courses.

### Education

- •Relevant Courses in Data Analysis.
- •Bachelor of Languages and Translation (Spanish & English) Octuber 6 University-EGYPT. 2013 –2017

## Languages

Arabic: NativeEnglish: Advanced